3dmark.com 2018-12-23

# Privacy Policy | UL Benchmarks

We are committed to protecting your privacy and personal data when you visit our websites and use our products and services. Our Privacy Policy explains what information we collect, how we use that information, and our legal basis for do so. Our Privacy Policy also explains how your information may be shared and your rights to the information you provide to us, including how you can access, update, or delete the information we hold about you.

By using our Services, you’re acknowledging you have agreed to our Terms and conditions and that you have read and understood this Privacy Policy and our Cookie Policy.

## Who we are

This policy applies to the UL Benchmarks homepage and [3dmark.com](https://www.3dmark.com/) websites and all of the currently supported software products and services offered on those sites—collectively, our "Services".

This policy complements the [global UL privacy policy](https://www.ul.com/customer-resources/online-policies/privacy-policy/). Where there are differences, this policy shall apply for our Services.

Unless indicated otherwise, this policy does not apply to other websites, products, services, or companies that you might interact with on or through our Services.

Our Services are provided by Futuremark OY trading as UL. We are based in Finland.

If you are a resident of the European Union, Futuremark OY is the controller of your personal data for the purposes of EU data protection law.

## Contact

If you have questions, suggestions or concerns about our privacy policy and data protection practices, please contact us:

Jukka Mäkinen  
UL  
Niittytaival 13  
02200 ESPOO  
FINLAND

## Complaints

Should you wish to raise a concern about our use of your information, you have the right to lodge a complaint with your local supervisory authority.

* * *

## Information that we collect

We may need to collect, store, and process certain information about you in order to provide you with our Services.

### 3dmark.com account

You can create an account on 3dmark.com to save and manage your benchmark results. You may prefer to choose a username that does not contain personal information such as your real name.

  * If you register directly with us, we will collect and store your email address and chosen username.
  * If you choose to sign in through Google, we will collect and store your email address and chosen username.
  * If you choose to sign in through Facebook, we will collect and store your chosen username. You can optionally choose to add an email address to your account.
  * If you choose to sign in through Steam, we will collect your Steam ID and your chosen username. You can optionally choose to add an email address to your account.

Your username appears alongside public benchmark results you submit to our Services. You can hide individual benchmark results using the option on the result page, or you can choose to hide all new results automatically on your [3dmark.com account settings](https://www.3dmark.com/settings) page.

You can change the email address and username associated with your account on your [3dmark.com account settings](https://www.3dmark.com/settings) page. You can also choose to delete your account if you wish.

### Applications

To help us improve our products, our software may collect and report log files, crash reports, and other anonymous statistical information.

We use Google Analytics and Firebase to collect anonymous statistical information about how people use our Services.

  * You can opt out of Google Analytics [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).
  * To opt out of Firebase Analytics in the 3DMark and VRMark Android apps, go to the Settings screen and disable Analytics.

### Benchmark results

When you use our benchmarking software, we collect information about the hardware and software specifications of your computer or mobile device or other hardware under test. This system information does not contain any personally identifiable information about you.

If you have an account on 3dmark.com, your benchmark results will be associated with your username. If you do not have an account, your results will be submitted anonymously.

You can add an optional description to each one of your benchmark results. If you choose to include personal information in a result's description then we will determine that you have given us your consent to store and display the information in our Services.

We may share aggregated, non-personally identifiable information about benchmark results publicly and with our partners. For example, we may share information to show trends about the general use of our Services.

### Result database services

We may give third parties access to anonymized data in our benchmark results database by creating services that make it possible to ask specific questions of our Database, (about things like PC configurations with a specific graphic cards, for example), and producing reports summarizing the data regarding these different kinds of computer configurations. We never attach personal user information to these services.

### Hall of Fame

Exceptional benchmark scores may qualify for our Hall of Fame. If you have a 3dmark.com account and you submit a qualifying score, it will appear in the Hall of Fame alongside your username, your country, and information about your computer hardware. If you do not want your results to appear in the Hall of Fame, you should hide your results as described above.

### Online Store

When you purchase one of our products from our online store, we ask for your name, email address, country, and credit card information in order to validate and fulfil your purchase.

To prevent fraud, your information will be subjected to an automated risk review, which may result in your purchase being declined.

Our online store is powered by a third-party provider called FastSpring that specializes in the safe and secure sale and fulfillment of software and other digital products.

For all purchases, FastSpring employs Verisign SSL Certificates that meet the highest standard in the Internet security industry for secure transactions.

FastSpring is compliant with the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI DSS). FastSpring does not store credit card numbers, so there is no chance of your credit card number being accessed or stolen.

You can find out more about purchasing through FastSpring [here](https://fastspring.com/purchasing-through-fastspring/), and read its privacy policy [here](https://fastspring.com/privacy/).

### Customer Support

Our customer support pages are powered by a third-party provider called GetSatisfaction. By default, your posts on GetSatisfaction will be visible to other users. This helps other people find answers without having to submit support requests of their own. If you prefer, you can choose the "Send Privately" option when submitting your request.

Through GetSatisfaction, we will have access to your username, email address, and any other personal information you include in your profile or support requests. We do not use that information for any purpose other than helping you with your request.

You have to create an account with GetSatisfaction before you can submit a support request to us. You should contact GetSatisfaction directly if you wish to exercise your rights to the data they hold about you. While we can delete individual support posts, we are not able to delete or change your GetSatisfaction account in any way. You can read GetSatisfaction's privacy policy [here](https://getsatisfaction.com/corp/privacy-policy/).

### Newsletters, mailing lists and email marketing

If you give us your consent, we will collect and store your personal information so that we can send you news, information and offers related to UL's products and services by email. You can withdraw your consent at any time.

### Online Forms

We have some forms on our site for contacting us, requesting quotes, and for gathering feedback from our users. We will use the information your provide through the form such as your name, email address, location, and/or employer to respond to your request.

### Surveys

We may run surveys on our Services to gather feedback and opinions from our users. By choosing to complete a survey, you consent for us to collect and store any personal information that you provide in order to administer the survey. You may be asked to provide information such as your name, email address. age, location, gender, and other demographic information.

When the survey is complete, personal data is anonymized, and the data is aggregated and analysed to produce trends and insights that help us improve our Services.

### Contests

We may run contests, prize draws and product giveaways on or through our Services. You may need to provide personal information to us in order to enter a contest. If you choose to enter, you acknowledge that you have agreed to the contest terms and conditions and that you have given us your consent to process your data.

We do not require you to opt-in to receive marketing messages in order to enter a contest.

If you're selected as a winner, you will be notified by email at the address you provided. Depending on the prize, you may be asked to provide a mailing address and phone number so that your prize can be delivered.

Winners' details, including name, username and/or general location may be shared by us in press releases, social media, or other public channels.

When a contest is complete and all prizes have been fulfilled, personal data related to the contest entrants is deleted.

### Technical information

We collect information from your browser, computer, or mobile device, which provide us with technical information when you access or use the Services. This technical information includes device and network information, cookies, log files and analytics information.

### Log files

Our Services produce log files, which we use to administer and protect our Services, to diagnose problems, and to analyze aggregated trends and broad demographic patterns. These log files may include your IP address, location, and device information.

We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our websites, in other words for normal web statistics. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information.

### Cookies

We use cookies and similar technologies to improve your experience, provide personalized content, remember your preferences, and better understand how you use our Services. This site uses third party cookies from our social media, advertising, and analytics partners.

You can manage your cookie preferences for benchmarks.ul.com here and for 3dmark.com [here](https://www.3dmark.com/cookie-policy). You can also use the settings on your browser or mobile device. Not accepting cookies may make certain features of the Services unavailable to you.

For more information about our use of cookies to protect and improve our Services, please read our Cookie Policy.

* * *

## Our lawful bases for processing your data

Data protection law in Europe requires a lawful basis for collecting and retaining personal information from citizens or residents of the European Economic Area. Our lawful bases include:

### Consent

If you give us your consent, we will collect and store your personal information so that we can send you news, information and offers related to UL's products and services by email. You can withdraw your consent at any time.

If you choose to make your personal information public through our services, for example, through your choice of username or other account profile information, we determine that you have given us your consent to store and display such information. You can withdraw your consent by changing your username or by deleting your account.

If you choose to enter a contest on or through our Services, we determine that you have given us your consent to process your data so that we may administer the contest. You can withdraw your consent by writing to [UL.BenchmarkPrivacy@ul.com](mailto:UL.BenchmarkPrivacy@UL.com).

If you choose to complete a survey on or through our Services, we determine that you have given us your consent to process your data in line with this policy and the stated purpose of the survey. You can withdraw your consent by writing to [UL.BenchmarkPrivacy@ul.com](mailto:UL.BenchmarkPrivacy@UL.com).

### Contract

In certain circumstances, we will need your personal data in order to deliver our Services to you or to respond to a request that you ask of us.

We use Contract as the lawful basis for processing your personal data when you create a user account for our Services, when you request a quote, when you buy software or services from us, when you request customer support, or when you otherwise contact us with a request that requires a response.

### Legal obligation

We may need to collect and use your data to comply with a legal obligation, a court order, or to exercise and defend legal claims. For example, tax laws require us to retain records of your purchases made through our Services.

### Legitimate interests

This is a term in data protection law that means we have a good and fair reason to use your data in ways which do not hurt your interests, freedom, or rights.

We may use your personal information including your identity, device, and location information to prevent fraud and abuse, to keep our Services secure, or to protect the rights, property or safety of UL, our employees, our users or the public.

We use aggregated, anonymous data to analyze how users interact with our Services so that we can understand which elements are working well and which are not. This allows us to develop and improve the quality of our Services for all our users.

* * *

## Your rights

Users residing in certain countries, including the EU, have certain rights regarding their personal information. Except where an exception or exemption applies, these rights include the ability to access, correct, and request deletion of your personal information. While these rights are not required by law globally, all users of this this website and our software can manage their personal information as described below.

We may ask you to verify your identity before we act on your request. We may reject requests that are unreasonably repetitive, require disproportionate technical effort, (for example, developing a new system or fundamentally changing an existing practice), risk the privacy of others, or would be extremely impractical (for instance, requests concerning information residing on backup tapes).

Where we can provide information access and correction, we will do so for free, except where it would require a disproportionate effort. We aim to protect the information in our Services from accidental or malicious destruction. Because of this, when you delete information from our Services, we may not immediately delete residual copies from our active servers, and we may not remove information from our backup systems.

### How to exercise your rights

You can exercise your rights described below by writing to [UL.BenchmarkPrivacy@ul.com](mailto:UL.BenchmarkPrivacy@UL.com). If you wish to exercise your rights to your data across the whole of UL, you should submit a [Data Subject Access Request](https://app-de.onetrust.com/app/#/webform/e348820f-6ffc-48f0-aa9f-2d80a79304fc).

### Your right to be informed

This policy forms a key part of your right to be informed about the collection and processing of your data.

### Your right of access

You have the right to ask for a copy of the personal data we hold about your as well as other supplementary information. We will reply to your request within 30 days.

### Your right to data portability

You have the right to receive data you have provided to us in a structured, commonly used, and machine readable format. You can also ask us to transmits this data directly to another data controller.

### Your right to rectification

You have the right to correct information we hold about you that is wrong or incomplete. We will reply to your request within 30 days.

### Your right to erasure

You have the right to have your personal data erased or deleted. This is also known as the ‘right to be forgotten’.

Please note that this right right does not apply when we are required to keep your data to comply with a legal obligation or for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

You can delete your 3dmark.com account using the option on the Settings screen.  For other data that we hold about you, you can write to [UL.BenchmarkPrivacy@ul.com](mailto:UL.BenchmarkPrivacy@UL.com) or you can submit a [Data Subject Access Request](https://app-de.onetrust.com/app/#/webform/e348820f-6ffc-48f0-aa9f-2d80a79304fc).

### Your right to restrict processing

As an alternative to erasure, you have the right to restrict the processing of your personal data in certain circumstances. We will reply to your request within 30 days.

### Your right to object

Where we process your information based on our legitimate interests explained above, you can object to this processing in certain circumstances. In such cases, we will cease processing your information unless we have compelling legitimate grounds to continue processing or where it is needed for legal reasons.

Where you have previously provided your consent, you have the right to withdraw your consent to the processing of your information at any time. In certain cases, we may continue to process your information after you have withdrawn consent if we have a legal basis to do so or if your withdrawal of consent was limited to certain processing activities.

Should you wish to raise a concern about our use of your information, you have the right to do so with your local supervisory authority.

### Your rights in relation to automated decision making and profiling

You can submit a [Data Subject Access Request](https://app-de.onetrust.com/app/#/webform/e348820f-6ffc-48f0-aa9f-2d80a79304fc) if you think that you have been legally or significantly affected as a result of automated decision making or profiling by us.

* * *

## Security

We have security measures in place to protect against unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction of the information we hold. When you enter sensitive information on our site, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer (SSL) technology. We restrict access to personal information to a small number of UL employees.

We are committed to safeguarding the security of user information that is retained on our servers. Nevertheless, determined individuals may uncover such information and disclose it. For this reason, we cannot guarantee against unauthorized access to the information we hold about you.

## Retention

In most cases, we will keep your information as long as it is necessary to provide our Services to you or until you ask us to delete it, whichever comes first. User accounts on 3dmark.com are automatically deleted after five years of inactivity.

We may also retain and use your information when it is required to comply with our legal obligations, prevent fraud, collect fees, resolve disputes, enforce our agreements, protect our legal rights, or take other actions permitted by law.

Information about you that is no longer necessary or relevant to provide our Services may be de-associated with your name and other identifiers and then aggregated with other non-personal data to produce insights and statistics that help us improve our Services.

Aggregated, anonymized and pseudonymized information that we collect to improve our Services, protect the safety and security of our Services, or comply with legal obligations may be retained indefinitely.

## Transfers

The Services are operated from Finland. If you are located outside of the European Union and choose to use our Services or provide information to us, you acknowledge and understand that your information will be transferred, processed and stored in the EU, as necessary to provide the Services and perform the Terms of Service. EU privacy laws may differ from those in your jurisdiction.

The company providing the Services is owned by UL LLC, which operates from the United States. If you are located outside of the United States and choose to use the Services or provide information to us, you acknowledge and understand that your information may be transferred, processed and stored in the United States. United States privacy laws may not be as protective as those in your jurisdiction.

## Children

We do not knowingly collect any personal information from children under the age of 13 and children under 13 are not permitted to register for an account or use our Services.

If you believe that a child has provided us with personal information, please contact us at [UL.BenchmarkPrivacy@ul.com](mailto:UL.BenchmarkPrivacy@UL.com). If we become aware that a child under age 13 has provided us with personally identifiable information, we will delete it.

## Other UL Sites

Our Services are part of a larger network of sites and services operated by UL and its partners, the “Other Sites.” The Other Sites may have a similar look and feel as these Services, but they have their own terms and privacy policies.

If you interact with the Other Sites, your information may be stored, processed, or shared outside of these Services. We are not responsible for the personal information you choose to submit through the Other Sites.

You can submit a [Data Subject Access Request](https://app-de.onetrust.com/app/#/webform/e348820f-6ffc-48f0-aa9f-2d80a79304fc) should you wish to exercise your rights to your data across all of UL's services.

## Changes

We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time. When there are significant changes to this policy, we will give notice on the UL Benchmarks homepage. If the changes affect the way we use your personally identifiable information, we will notify you where possible. If you object to any of the changes to this Privacy Policy, you should stop using the Services and delete your account.
